Pooja Agarwal

Frontend Developer

I am a Frontend Developer with 2+ years of combined experience in software development, and testing. I have a passion for learning, evidenced by successful transition from test engineering to frontend development and continuous self-improvement through freelance and personal hobby projects.

apooja.dev21@gmail.com +91 9026343013 Lucknow, India

apooja.dev/

linkedin.com/in/poojaagarwal21

github.com/apooja21

WORK EXPERIENCE

Contract Frontend Developer Sijal In Stiches LLP

04/2021 - 03/2022

- Created user interfaces with Angular, TypeScript and HTML/CSS to ensure responsive design across platforms, improved web page performance by 25-50%,
- Implemented PrimeNG Angular UI component library to ensure more efficient usage of the codebase for better and faster development,
- Created landing pages, dashboards for the ecommerce website,
- Collaborated with backend developers to integrate frontend components with back-end APIs,
- Maintained strict budgetary and scheduling guidelines to satisfy customers with high-quality, targeted designs.

Test Engineer Wipro Limited

11/2018 - 11/2020

- Developed and implemented comprehensive test automation framework, resulting in 20% decrease in test cycles and improved coverage to 60% from 40%,
- Executed various manual and automated tests, and tracked potential software problems via bug tracking system,
- Identified and tracked defects with Jira and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests
- Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality,
- Created automation scripts using Parasoft SOA Test tool and Jython,
- Kept scripts and test cases updated with current requirements for future reference and use.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science and Engineering

Shri Ramswaroop Memorial University

08/2014 - 05/2018

GPA - 7.38

Projects - Vision Share

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Age of Empire Stats - React, MUI Component Library

apooja.dev/aoe2-stats/

Workout Buddy – React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, JWT Authentication

github.com/apooja21/workout-buddy-jwt-authentication

Plant Store Website - HTML, CSS, Javascript

apooja.dev/plant-store-website

Todo List App - React

• apooja.dev/todo-list-app/

CERTIFICATES

Modern React with Redux Udemy Certification

The Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy Certification

Android Application Development (07/2017)

Summer Training at Training@Infoseek

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Attempted Civil Services Exam from April 2022 to October 2024

Indulged in my passion for painting - digital painting

Freelanced on various web development projects, showcasing skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript